Hello friends,
welcome to the Wealth Yagya channel. Today we are going to see the news in the market that the
company ICICI Lombard is going to
acquire the Indian AXA General Insurance Company.
Before that, if
you are new to this channel, then
subscribe to this channel and don't forget to press the bell icon so that
you will get the notification of new videos as soon as possible.
Friends, the Competition Commission of India (
CCI) has
given approval for the acquisition on Monday. The
general insurance business of Indian
AXA is the business of Indian AXA General
Insurance. The
company is going to acquire ICIS Lombard General Insurance. In the
month of August this year, that is,
in August 2020, the board of
directors of both the board of directors of ICI Lombard General Insurance
and the
board of directors of Indian AXA General Insurance have
given approval for this approval merger and the
general insurance business of Indian AXA is the business of Indian AXA.  It is going to be
demerged from Bharatiya AXA
and it is going to be merged with ICICI Lombard.
In this merger and acquisition,
not only the approval of CCI is required, but after that the
approval of Insurance Regulatory Development Authority of India i.e. IRDI is required, then the
approval of SEBI i.e. Securities and
Exchange Board of India is required, then the
approval of Stock Exchanges is required, then the
approval of Reserve Bank of India is required and the
approval of NCLT is also required for this and
after the approval of the shareholders of both, that is, ICICI Lombard and Bharatiya AXA General Insurance, then
both of these will be merged.
After the merger, if the shareholders of Bharatiya AXA have
115 shares of Bharatiya
AXA, then they will
get two shares of ICICI Lombard.
Bharatiya Excise, which is a general insurance
company, is a joint venture with Bharatiya.
Enterprises Bharti Enterprises has a 51%
stake and French insurance company
AXA has a 49% stake. As
mentioned earlier, if
all the approvals are received from IRDIA,
Reserve Bank of India,
SEBI, then after the
merger,
both Bharti Exam and AXA will exit the
non-life insurance business.
If both of them merge, the
combined company will have a
market share of 87% on a pro
forma basis.
After the approval of both of them,
Bharat ICICI Lombard will get to use the distribution strength of Bharat ICICI Lombard and the
distribution network of Bharat ICICI Lombard.
This news is
good for the shareholders of ICICI Lombard.
I have brought it to you as I received this news.  If
you like the channel, then
like this video and if
you are new to the channel, then subscribe to the channel
and don't forget to press the bell icon so
that you will get the notification of the new video as soon as possible.
Okay
friends, let's meet again with a new
video like this. Until then, Jai Hind, Jai
Maharashtra.